Escape from Sobibor is a drama, thriller, war film directed by Jack Gold.
The true story of WWII's notorious Sobibor Nazi death camp, where a courageous
inmate orchestrates and leads the escape of over 300 prisoners.
Leon Feldhendler, played by Alan Arkin.
Luka, played by Joanna Pacula.
Alexander 'Sasha' Pechersky, played by Rutger Hauer.
Hauptscharführer Gustav Wagner, played by Hartmut Becker.
Itzhak Lichtman, played by Jack Shepherd.
Samuel, played by Emil Wolk.
Escape from Sobibor is a 1987 British television
film which aired on ITV and CBS.
It is the story of the mass escape from the Nazi extermination camp at Sobibor, the most successful uprising by Jewish
prisoners of German extermination camps (uprisings also took place at Auschwitz-Birkenau and Treblinka).
The film was directed by Jack Gold and shot in Avala, Yugoslavia (now Serbia).
The full 176-minute version shown in the UK on 10 May 1987 followed a
143-minute version shown in the United States on 12 April 1987.
The script, by Reginald Rose, was based on Richard Rashke's 1983 book of the same name, along with a manuscript by Sobibor survivor
Thomas Blatt, "From the Ashes of Sobibor", and a book by Stanisław Szmajzner, Inferno in Sobibor, also a survivor.
Alan Arkin, Joanna Pacuła, and Rutger Hauer starred in the film.
The film received a Golden Globe Award for Best Miniseries or Television Film and Hauer received a
Golden Globe Award for Best Actor in a Supporting Role—Television Film or Miniseries.
(The film tied with Poor Little Rich Girl: The Barbara Hutton Story.) Esther Raab was a camp
survivor who had assisted Rashke with his book and served as a technical consultant.
The film explores themes of concentration camp,
world war ii, brutality, poland, smoke.
The tone is intense and dark and emotional.